<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<match><id>2010_FIFA_WORLD_CUP_special_2</id><docUri>/matches/2010_FIFA_WORLD_CUP_special_1.xml</docUri><abstract>A generated bit of match data for a fictitious 2010 world cup</abstract><report>The final was played on 11 July 2010 at Soccer City, Johannesburg. Spain defeated the Netherlands 1–0, after an extra time goal by Andrés Iniesta.
  The win gave Spain its first World Cup title. It was the first time since England in 1966 that the winners of the final wore their second-choice strip.
  The match had the most yellow cards awarded in a World Cup final, more than doubling the previous record for a final, set when Argentina and West Germany shared six cards in 1986.
  Fourteen yellow cards were awarded (nine of which to the Netherlands), and John Heitinga of the Netherlands was sent off for a second yellow. 
  One yellow card was for Nigel de Jong's studs-up kick to the chest of Xabi Alonso during the first half, for which Rob Hughes of the New York Times, among others, 
  believed the referee should have given a red card.
  The referee, Howard Webb, later said after reviewing the foul that it should have been a red card, but that his view during play was partially obstructed.
  The Netherlands had several chances to score, most notably in the 62nd minute when Arjen Robben was released by Wesley Sneijder putting him one-on-one with Spain's goalkeeper Iker Casillas, 
  but Casillas pushed the shot wide with an outstretched leg. 
  Meanwhile, for Spain, Sergio Ramos missed a free header from a corner kick when he was unmarked.
  Dutch captain Giovanni van Bronckhorst was substituted in the 105th minute by Edson Braafheid; 
  Real Madrid midfielder Rafael van der Vaart, who had come on as a substitute in the 99th minute for Nigel de Jong, took over as captain for the last 15 minutes. 
  From the 109th minute, the Dutch played with 10 men due to Heitinga's second yellow card. 
  With a penalty shootout seeming inevitable, Jesús Navas sprinted into opposing territory and began a series of passes that led to Iniesta finally breaking the deadlock four minutes before the end of extra time, 
  scoring with a right footed half-volleyed shot low to the goalkeeper's right after receiving a pass from Cesc Fàbregas on the right of the penalty area.
  Just before the goal was scored, the Dutch team had a free kick that hit the wall (apparently taking a deflection off Fàbregas) before going out.
  Despite the deflection, which should have given possession and a corner kick to the Dutch, a goal kick was given to Spain, starting the play that led to the goal. 
  The Dutch, however, momentarily had possession of the ball near the Spanish penalty area in between the goal kick and Iniesta's goal. 
  Joris Mathijsen was yellow-carded for his strong protests to the referee after the goal, and other Dutch players criticised Webb for this decision after the match.
  Iniesta was yellow-carded for the removal of his team shirt when celebrating his goal. 
  Underneath he had a white vest with the handwritten message: "Dani Jarque siempre con nosotros" ("Dani Jarque, always with us").
  </report><goals>4</goals></match>
