<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Larissa Mabel Riquelme Frutos, usually known as Larissa Riquelme (born 22 February 1985) is a Paraguayan model and actress at the city theatre in the Paraguayan capital Asunción. She is one of the highest-paid models in Paraguay.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Larissa Riquelme (22 de febrero de 1985) es una modelo paraguaya. Se hizo conocida en el Mundial de fútbol 2010 en Sudáfrica donde fue apodada como La novia del mundial.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_controversies</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup generated various controversies, including some from before the tournament started. Most centred around refereeing.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_matches</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup was an international football tournament held in South Africa from 11 June until 11 July 2010. The 32 national teams involved in the tournament together played a total of 64 matches starting from the group stage matches and progressing to the knockout stage matches, with teams eliminated through the various progressive stages. Rest days were allocated during the various stages to allow players recovery during the tournament. Preliminary events were also held in celebration of the World Cup event.All times shown are in South African Standard Time (UTC+02).</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Listen Up! The Official 2010 FIFA World Cup Album is a collaboration by various artists, both local African and international. The album was released on May 31, 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Listen Up! The Official 2010 FIFA World Cup Album is een verzamelalbum dat in 2010 verscheen als officieel album bij het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 in Zuid-Afrika dat georganiseerd werd door de FIFA.Het album bevat samenwerkingen tussen internationaal bekende artiesten met minder bekende Afrikaanse artiesten en Aziatische artiesten. Ook de officiële tune van het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal, Waka waka (This time for Africa), staat op het album. De nummers worden ook ten gehore gebracht op het afsluitende concert op 11 juli 2010 voor de finale van het wk.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">A lekarapa (plural makarapa) is a hand-cut and hand-painted hard hat worn by sports fans. They belong to the typical South African football fan's supporters gear, and are increasingly popular with fans of other sports. Sport fans spend hours to sculpt and paint their makarapa in the colours and emblem of their clubs or country. Besides the makarapa, fans also wear giant glasses or have shields with team slogans and logos. It is generally accepted that Alfred "Lux" Baloyi is the originator of the makarapa as a fan gear or tool as it is known today, and is the owner of the 'Original Baloyi Makarapa' trademark. Many makarapa artists in South Africa make a modest living from designing makarapa, selling them to sports fans of all kinds. With the 2010 FIFA World Cup, the international profile and availability of the makarapa has increased greatly.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">De Makarapa is een handgesneden en beschilderde helm. Het is een uit Zuid-Afrika afkomstige voetbalfanuitrusting, en het wordt steeds populairder bij fans van andere sporten. Sportfans spenderen uren om de makarapa uit te snijden en te beschilderen in de kleuren en logo's van hun club of land. Behalve de makarapa dragen fans ook meestal enorme brillen of schilden met slogans en logos. Het is algemeen geaccepteerd dat Alfred "Lux" Baloyi de uitvinder is van de Makarapa zoals we hem nu kennen. en tevens eigenaar van het 'Original Baloyi Makarapa' trademark. Veel makarapakunstenaars in Zuid-Afrika kunnen redelijk rondkomen van het vervaardigen en verkopen van makarapa's aan sportfans. Met het WK voetbal zal de makarapa wereldwijd bekend worden.De oorsprong van de naam makarapa gaat terug tot eind jaren '70, begin jaren '80. Makarapa (enkelvoud: lekarapa) betekent gastarbeider en wordt geassocieerd met de helmen die ze droegen in de mijnen van Witwatersrand. Tegenwoordig is de naam synoniem voor deze gedecoreerde helm. De makarapa heeft drie functies: het laat zien dat de drager een fan van iets is, het is een individueel stuk kunstwerk en het is een commercieel promotieartikel, omdat het veel media-aandacht in stadions trekt. Bierbrouwer Heineken speelt daar op in door de Nederlandse makarapa te introduceren, genaamd de pletterpet, wat Zuid-Afrikaans is voor helm. Ook wordt de makarapa gebruikt ter bescherming van het hoofd tegen projectielen, de eigenlijke reden dat hij gedragen werd.De makarapa was aanwezig tijdens de uitreiking van de FIFA Worldcup 2010 in Zürich. In september 2009 kreeg Sepp Blatter een makarapa cadeau tijdens een FIFA-inspectie. De prijs van een makarapa, gemaakt door een kunstenaar, varieert tussen de 180 en 500 Zuid-Afrikaanse rand, dat is € 18,00 tot € 52,00, afhankelijk van de kwaliteit en complexiteit van het kunstwerk.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Un makarapa est un casque de chantier à corne coupé et peint à la main qui est porté par les supporters de football sud-africains.Portail de l’Afrique du Sud Portail de l’Afrique du Sud Portail du football Portail du football</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Paul (pronunciación: /paʊl/) (nacido en enero de 2008 y muerto el 26 de octubre de 2010) fue un pulpo empleado como oráculo para predecir los resultados de la selección alemana de fútbol en competiciones internacionales, concretamente en la Eurocopa 2008 y en el Mundial de Fútbol 2010, donde también fue empleado para predecir otros resultados, acertando los ocho emparejamientos que se le propusieron. Debido a la notable trascendencia mediática que le otorgó este hecho, surgieron en ciertos países algunos nombres con los que fue denominado y que hacían referencia a sus supuestas facultades adivinatorias; así en alemán fue conocido como das Krakenorakel y en inglés como the psychic octopus, expresiones que en lengua española significan «pulpo oráculo» y «pulpo médium», respectivamente. Después del campeonato mundial de fútbol, sus cuidadores comunicaron que no volvería a realizar más pronósticos.A pesar de haber nacido en el Sea Life Centre de Weymouth, una localidad del sur de Inglaterra, vivió en las instalaciones del Sea Life Centre en Oberhausen, Alemania. Su nombre fue tomado del título de un poema del escritor alemán de literatura infantil Boy Lornsen, titulado «Der Tintenfisch Paul Oktopus» (El calamar Paul, el pulpo). Según el director del acuario, Paul demostró pronto una destacada inteligencia, y afirmó que su peculiar forma de mirar a los visitantes llevó a sus cuidadores a intentar comprobar su talento.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Paul de Octopus (2008 in de Atlantische Oceaan in Weymouth, Dorset - 26 oktober 2010 in Oberhausen, Duitsland) was een in het Sea Life Centre te Oberhausen, Duitsland woonachtige achtarm, die in de zomer van 2010 dankzij de internationale pers grote bekendheid verwierf als voorspeller van voetbaluitslagen van vooral het Duitse voetbalelftal tijdens het Wereldkampioenschap Voetbal in Zuid-Afrika. Hij wist de uitslag van alle zeven wedstrijden van het Duitse team juist te voorspellen en bovendien de uitslag van de finale van Nederland tegen Spanje. Ook tijdens het Europees kampioenschap voetbal 2008 was hij reeds actief. Hij maakte toen echter twee fouten, waaronder de voorspelling van de winnaar van de finale, waar hij ten onrechte Duitsland in plaats van Spanje als winnaar aanwees. Paul was overigens niet het enige dier dat voorspellingen deed over finale van het WK 2010.Daags na de finale van het wereldkampioenschap 2010 heeft het Sealife Aquarium in Oberhausen bekendgemaakt dat Paul de Octopus als voorspeller met pensioen is gegaan. Ten tijde van zijn pensionering was hij reeds vrij oud voor een octopus, namelijk tweeënhalf jaar. Hij was 50 centimeter lang.Het dorp Carballiño in de Noord-Spaanse regio Galicië, dat 14.000 inwoners telt, heeft Paul op 13 juli 2010 tot ereburger uitgeroepen. De onderscheiding, een doorzichtige urn met het wapen van Carballiño werd persoonlijk door burgemeester Carlos Montes in Oberhausen aan Paul overhandigd. Carlos Montes had het Duitse Sea Life Centre 35.000 euro geboden om Paul over te nemen en als toeristenlokkertje in Carballiño te plaatsen. Paul bleef gewoon in zijn eigen aquarium te Oberhausen waar hij op 26 oktober 2010 dood werd aangetroffen door zijn verzorgers.Begin 2011 werd bekendgemaakt dat er een gedenkplaats zou komen voor Paul de Octopus.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Paul le poulpe ou Paul la pieuvre, surnommé « l’oracle d’Oberhausen » (Weymouth, 26 janvier 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 octobre 2010) est une pieuvre commune mâle maintenue en captivité à l’aquarium Sea Life d’Oberhausen en Allemagne. Paul est renommé pour le spectacle de ses prédictions du résultat des matchs de l’équipe d'Allemagne de football lors du Championnat d’Europe 2008 et de la Coupe du monde 2010, dont il a également désigné le vainqueur. Paul le poulpe faisait connaître ses choix en ouvrant une boîte aux couleurs de l'équipe gagnante. Sur quatorze prédictions au total, douze se sont révélées exactes, dont toutes celles émises au cours de la Coupe du Monde 2010 qui l'aura fait accéder à la postérité.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul the Octopus (hatched in 2008, died October 2010) was a common octopus living in a tank at a Sea Life Centre in Oberhausen, Germany, who was used as an animal oracle to predict the results of football matches, usually international matches in which Germany was playing. He came to worldwide attention with his accurate predictions in the 2010 World Cup.During a divination, Paul was presented with two boxes containing food, each marked with the flag of a national football team in an upcoming match. He chose the box with the flag of the winning team in several of Germany's six Euro 2008 matches, and all seven of their matches in the 2010 World Cup—with Germany's third place playoff win over Uruguay on 10 July. His success rate rose to 85 percent, with 11 out of 13 matches correctly predicted. He predicted a win for Spain against the Netherlands in the World Cup final on 11 July by eating the mussel in the box with the Spanish flag on it.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poor_People's_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Poor People's World Cup was an event organised by a South African social movement in response to the 2010 FIFA World Cup in South Africa.The event was created by the Western Cape Anti-Eviction Campaign who believed that the World Cup has had a negative impact on poor communities in Cape Town, via evictions, relocations, and not being allowed to trade near the new football stadiums.The event consisted of 36 teams from poor South African communities, and each represents an official World Cup country. The first game was on 13 June 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Santo,_Sam_and_Ed's_Cup_Fever!</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Santo, Sam and Ed's Cup Fever! was an association football themed comedy television show in Australia on SBS. The nightly panel-style show was produced by Working Dog Productions and aired for the duration of the 2010 FIFA World Cup. The show was hosted by Santo Cilauro, Sam Pang and Ed Kavalee, with Rob Sitch making several guest appearances. Segments included Cup Update (a discussion of the previous day's World Cup matches), an interview with a special guest and various comedy sketches. Socceroos midfielder Mark Bresciano featured in his own diary segment. He also announced that he had signed for Serie A club Lazio during an interview on the show. Other regular segments included ‘Take on my Nuts’, ‘Not Even Close’ and ‘The Rivaldo Award’ which poked fun at World Cup proceedings and football in general. The show also had segments filmed at the World Cup by correspondent Tony Wilson.The show was well received by viewers and has a thriving Facebook community. Due to the show's popularity, fans are pushing for the show to continue in some form since completion of the 2010 FIFA World Cup. The spin-off show Santo, Sam and Ed’s Sports Fever! was picked up by the Seven Network and began airing from January 2012.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Een vuvuzela is een blaasinstrument dat vooral in Zuid-Afrika populair is onder voetbalfans en dat in 2010, naar aanleiding van het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, ook in veel andere landen bekend is geworden.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La vuvuzela, appelée lepatata en setswana, parfois francisée en vouvouzela, est une corne d'environ 70 centimètres de long, popularisée dans les années 1990 par les supporters des deux clubs de Soweto en Afrique du Sud : les Kaizer Chiefs (équipés du modèle jaune) et les Orlando Pirates (équipés du modèle noir et blanc). Elle a acquis une renommée internationale lors de la Coupe des confédérations 2009 et est omniprésente lors de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010, devenant un symbole de cette dernière, en même temps qu'un sujet de controverses à cause du bourdonnement incessant qu'elle génère pendant les matchs et leur retransmission.L'étymologie du nom est imprécise, soit du mot zoulou pour « faire du bruit », soit d'une onomatopée (« vou-vou ») imitant le son produit.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The vuvuzela /vuːvuːˈzɛlə/, also known as lepatata Mambu (its Tswana name), is a plastic horn, about 65 centimetres (2 ft) long, which produces a loud monotone note, typically around B♭ 3 (the B♭ below middle C). Some models are made in two parts to facilitate storage, and this design also allows pitch variation. Many types of vuvuzela, made by several manufacturers, may produce various intensity and frequency outputs. The intensity of these outputs depends on the blowing technique and pressure exerted.Traditionally made and inspired from a kudu horn, the vuvuzela was used to summon distant villagers to attend community gatherings. The vuvuzela is most used at football matches in South Africa, and it has become a symbol of South African football as the stadiums are filled with its sound. The intensity of the sound caught the attention of the global football community during the 2009 FIFA Confederations Cup in anticipation of South Africa hosting the 2010 FIFA World Cup.The vuvuzela has been the subject of controversy when used by spectators at football matches. Its high sound pressure levels at close range can lead to permanent hearing loss for unprotected ears after exposure, with a sound level of 120 dB(A) (the threshold of pain) at 1 metre (3.3 ft) from the device opening.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Una vuvuzela (en zulú, también conocida como lepatata en setsuana) es una especie de trompeta larga o corneta hecha de material plástico, utilizada por los aficionados para animar a sus equipos o clubes deportivos. Ha sido usada desde los años 60 en diferentes estadios del mundo sin ningún nombre específico, pero debe su nombre africano a que fue popularizada en tiempos de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 en Sudáfrica. Algunos timbres que produce son similares al barritar de un elefante o al zumbido de una abeja.Normalmente suena en nota Si Bemol. En español, ha de escribirse "vuvucela", según las reglas ortográficas españolas</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">"We're With You" is a Korean language song, and the third digital single by South Korean girl group Kara. It was part of SBS's 2010 FIFA World Cup campaign to cheer for the South Korean team in South Africa. The song was released on May 3, 2010. The first physical release of the song was on the Tour edition of the group's second Japanese album "Super Girl", released on April 11, 2012.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Write_the_Future</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Write the Future is an advert made by Nike football for the 2010 World Cup and directed by Mexican filmmaker Alejandro González Iñárritu for the UK based production company, Independent Films Limited. The full version is over three minutes in length and features football players Didier Drogba, Fabio Cannavaro, Wayne Rooney, Franck Ribéry, Ronaldinho, and Cristiano Ronaldo as its main players. All of the players play in a scenario during a World Cup match and after significant events occur, the players usually see a significant ripple effect outside the world of football. It airs during the 2010 FIFA World Cup. It can be considered a sequel to a previous advert entitled "Take It To The Next Level", which aired in 2008 for Euro 2008, and features similar people. It features the song "Hocus Pocus", by progressive rock band Focus. It was created by Wieden+Kennedy and written by Stuart Harkness and Freddie Powell.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Zakumi (16 juni 1994) is de mascotte van de Confederations Cup 2009 en het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, dat werd gehouden in Zuid-Afrika.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Zakumi (concebido 16 de Junio de 1994, imagen física de 16 años) fue la mascota oficial de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 que se realizó en Sudáfrica. Se trata de un leopardo africano antropomorfo con el pelo verde, diseñado por Andries Odendaal, un diseñador sudafricano originario de Ciudad del Cabo. Fue presentado el 22 de septiembre de 2008.Su nombre viene de “ZA” (el código ISO para Sudáfrica) y “kumi”, que significa diez en varias lenguas africanas. Tim Modise, portavoz oficial del comité organizador del mundial, informó que también puede traducirse como «ven aquí» en algunos idiomas africanos. La fecha de nacimiento de Zakumi coincide con el Día Internacional del Niño Africano, conocido en Sudáfrica como "Día de la juventud". En 2008 se informó que, al haber sido creado en 1994, “formaba parte de la generación libre sudafricana nacida en democracia”, ya que el año 1994 se considera el del nacimiento de la democracia en Sudáfrica.Los colores verdes y amarillos se asemejan a los de las selecciones deportivas sudafricanas, incluyendo el equipo nacional de fútbol. No obstante, y a diferencia de otras mascotas, no luce la camiseta de la selección nacional de fútbol de ese país, sino que viste una simple camiseta blanca con la inscripción “Sudáfrica 2010” (“South Africa 2010”, en inglés).El lema oficial de Zakumi, “Zakumi juega limpio”, se mostró en los tableros publicitarios digitales durante la Copa FIFA Confederaciones 2009 y en la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010. Divirtió a los aficionados durante las pausas de los partidos, y en las instalaciones oficiales de FIFA Fan Fest. Es el primer personaje en tener dos versiones del diseño, tanto bidimensional como tridimensional.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Zakumi est la mascotte officielle pour la Coupe du monde de football de 2010. C'est un léopard aux cheveux verts né le 16 juin 1994, qui a été présenté le 22 septembre 2008. Son nom vient de « ZA », l'abréviation internationale pour l'Afrique du Sud, et « kumi », un mot qui signifie « dix » dans diverses langues africaines.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Zakumi the Leopard (born (1994-06-16) 16 June 1994) was the Official Mascot for the 2010 FIFA World Cup. He is a cheerful, sporty anthropomorphized leopard with green hair, presented on 22 September 2008. His name comes from "ZA", the ISO 3166-1 alpha-2 code for South Africa, and "kumi", a word that means ten in several African languages, referencing the year 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Maware_Maware</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/album</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sign_of_a_Victory</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/album</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Waka_Waka_(This_Time_for_Africa)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/album</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/album</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Super_Girl_(Kara_album)</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diosa_Canales</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/associatedBand</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diosa_Canales</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/associatedMusicalArtist</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/birthDate</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1985-02-22+02:00</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/birthPlace</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Asunci%C3%B3n</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/birthPlace</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paraguay</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/birthYear</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1985+02:00</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/city</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Johannesburg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingMedia</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blu-ray_Disc</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingMedia</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/DVD</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingMedia</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nintendo_optical_discs</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingMedia</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Universal_Media_Disc</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingPlatform</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/IOS</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingPlatform</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/PlayStation_3</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingPlatform</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/PlayStation_Portable</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingPlatform</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Wii</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/computingPlatform</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Xbox_360</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Santo,_Sam_and_Ed's_Cup_Fever!</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/country</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Australia</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Santo,_Sam_and_Ed's_Cup_Fever!</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/creator</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Working_Dog_Productions</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/date</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">2010-07-11+02:00</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/developer</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/EA_Canada</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/developer</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/HB_Studios</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/developer</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Xbox_360</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2006_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/followingEvent</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/followingEvent</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2014_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Santo,_Sam_and_Ed's_Cup_Fever!</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/format</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Comedy</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/format</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Music_download</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/genre</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sports_game</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/genre</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dance-pop</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/genre</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dance-pop</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/genre</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/K-pop</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/height</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#decimal">1.6999999999999999556</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>