<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_H</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Group H of the 2010 FIFA World Cup began on 16 June and ended on 25 June 2010. The group consisted of reigning European champions Spain, Switzerland, Honduras and Chile.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_H</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Le groupe H de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010, qui se dispute en Afrique du Sud du 11 juin au 11 juillet 2010, comprend quatre équipes dont les deux premières se qualifient pour les huitièmes de finale de la compétition. Conformément au tirage au sort effectué le 4 décembre 2009 à Durban, les équipes du Chili (18e FIFA), d'Espagne (2e FIFA), du Honduras (38e FIFA) et de la Suisse (24e FIFA) composent ce groupe H.Le premier de ce groupe affrontera le second du Groupe G, et le deuxième de ce groupe affrontera le premier du Groupe G.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa is the official video game for the 2010 FIFA World Cup, published by EA Sports.The game was announced on 26 January 2010 during a GameSpot interview with Simon Humber, one of the producers of the game, and released April 27, 2010 in North America. 199 of the 204 teams that took part in the 2010 FIFA World Cup qualification are included in the game.A playable demo was released for Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 on 8 April 2010. It includes Italy and Spain as the playable teams, and features the new two-button control method intended to make the game accessible to players who are new to the FIFA series, and the ability to upload video replays to EA Football World.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">2010 FIFA World Cup es el videojuego oficial de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 creado por EA Sports. Fue anunciado el 26 de enero de 2010 y salió a la venta el 27 de abril de este mismo año para Xbox360, PSP, Wii y PlayStation 3.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">2010 FIFA World Cup is een spel ontwikkeld door EA Canada. Het staat in het teken van het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010. Het spel werd in Noord-Amerika uitgebracht op 27 april 2010, in Europa op 29 april 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_South_Africa_(video_game)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Coupe du monde de la FIFA : Afrique du Sud 2010 est un jeu vidéo de football développé et édité par Electronic Arts en 2010. Le jeu a été officiellement annoncé le 26 janvier 2010 par Simon Humber. Les 199 équipes nationales ayant pris part aux qualifications de la Coupe du Monde de la FIFA 2010 sont modélisées dans le jeu.Le jeu permet de disputer toute une coupe du monde, depuis les éliminatoires jusqu'à la phase finale. Il existe plusieurs modes dans le jeu: Coup d'envoi, Coupe du monde de la FIFA 2010, Deviens capitaine, En route pour la qualification, Coupe du monde la FIFA en ligne, Séance de tirs au but, Terrain d'entraînement, Ma coupe du monde de la FIFA 2010, Boutique coupe du monde de la FIFA 2010.Il est possible de jouer jusqu'à quatre joueurs ensemble ou une équipe contre l'autre sur la même console .</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_broadcasting_rights</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Cet article présente la liste des diffuseurs de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_broadcasting_rights</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">FIFA, through several companies, have sold the rights for the broadcast of 2010 FIFA World Cup to the following broadcasters.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_disciplinary_record</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">In the 2010 FIFA World Cup the main disciplinary action taken against players comes in the form of red and yellow cards.Any player picking up a red card is expelled from the pitch and automatically banned for his country's next match, whether via a straight red or second yellow. After a straight red card, FIFA will conduct a hearing and may extend this ban beyond one match. If the ban extends beyond the end of the World Cup finals (i.e. if a player is sent off in the match in which his team was eliminated), it must be served in the team's next competitive international match(es).Players also receive a one match ban if they pick up two yellow cards from the beginning of the group stage until the end of the quarterfinal matches at which point single yellow cards will be deleted. However, such a ban does not carry over beyond the World Cup finals if the second yellow card is collected in his team's last match of the tournament. Previously, players received a one game ban if they pick up two yellow cards within the group stage or within the knockout stage, however the rule was changed to give players a better chance to compete in the final should their team advance that far.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_event_effects</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup is the 19th FIFA World Cup, the premier international association football tournament, being held in South Africa from 11 June to 11 July. It is the first time the finals of the tournament have been staged in an African host nation as South Africa were selected as hosts following a bidding in 2004. The impact of the event itself transcend those bound by its athletic aspect and appeal, and the socioeconomic aspects of the tournament are far reaching.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_knockout_stage</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La phase à élimination directe de la Coupe du monde de football 2010 oppose les 16 équipes qualifiées à l'issue du premier tour. Ces équipes se rencontrent dans des matchs à élimination directe à partir des huitièmes de finale.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_knockout_stage</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The knockout stage of the 2010 FIFA World Cup was the second and final stage of the World Cup, following the group stage. It began on 26 June with the round of 16 matches, and ended on 11 July with the final match of the tournament held at Soccer City, Johannesburg, in which Spain beat the Netherlands 1–0 after extra time to claim their first World Cup. The top two teams from each group (16 in total) advanced to the knockout stage to compete in a single-elimination style tournament. A third place match is included and played between the two losing teams of the semi-finals.In the knockout stage (including the final), if a match was level at the end of 90 minutes, extra time of two periods (15 minutes each) would be played. If the score was still level after extra time, the match would be decided by a penalty shootout.All times listed are South African Standard Time (UTC+02)</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_officials</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Officials for the 2010 FIFA World Cup are selected from a pool of 30 trios of referees and assistant referees announced by the association football governing body, FIFA, on 5 February 2010. The final cut was selected from a group of 38 referees revealed in October 2008, themselves whittled down from an initial group of 54 selected for the Refereeing Assistance Programme in 2007. From the quarter-finals onwards, the pool of referees was reduced to 19.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_opening_ceremony</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La cérémonie d'ouverture de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010 a eu lieu le 11 juin 2010 au stade Soccer City à Johannesburg, deux heures avant le match d'ouverture du tournoi. Elle a duré 40 minutes, et a inclus 1500 artistes, dont Thandiswa Mazwai, Timothy Moloi, Hugh Masekela, Khaled, Femi Kuti, Osibisa, R. Kelly, Hip Hop Pantsula et le Soweto Gospel Choir.Malgré une santé fragile et ses 91 ans, l'ex-président sud-africain Nelson Mandela devait assister à la cérémonie d'ouverture, mais il a annulé sa venue après la mort de son arrière-petite-fille qui a été tué dans un accident de voiture plus tôt dans la journée. Aux côtés du président de la FIFA Sepp Blatter et de l'actuel président de l'Afrique du Sud Jacob Zuma, étaient présents lors de la cérémonie, le leader religieux sud-africain Desmond Tutu, le secrétaire général des Nations Unies Ban Ki-moon, le président mexicain Felipe Calderon, et le prince Albert II de Monaco.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_opening_ceremony</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The opening ceremony took place on 11 June at the Soccer City stadium in Johannesburg, two hours before the opening match of the tournament. It lasted 40 minutes, and included 1500 performers, including Thandiswa Mazwai, Timothy Moloi, Hugh Masekela, Khaled, Femi Kuti, Osibisa, R. Kelly, Hip Hop Pantsula and the Soweto Gospel Choir.Although in frail health and 91 years old, the ex-South African president Nelson Mandela was thought to be going to attend the opening ceremony, however he pulled out after the death of his great-granddaughter, who was killed in a car crash earlier in the day. Dignitaries that did attend the ceremony alongside the FIFA President Sepp Blatter and the current South African president Jacob Zuma, included the South African religious leader Desmond Tutu, the United Nations secretary-general Ban Ki-moon, the Mexican president Felipe Calderón, and Prince Albert of Monaco.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">En el proceso de clasificación para la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 los equipos compitieron por 32 plazas en la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010, con una plaza destinada a su sede, Sudáfrica. Las seis confederaciones de la FIFA compartieron los 31 cupos restantes. La distribución fue la siguiente: Europa (UEFA): 13 plazas África (CAF): 5 plazas (más Sudáfrica, clasificada automáticamente por su calidad de país sede, dando un total de 6 países) Sudamérica (Conmebol): 4,5 plazas Norte, Centroamérica y el Caribe (Concacaf): 3,5 plazas Asia (AFC): 4,5 plazas Oceanía (OFC): 0,5 plazaEuropa y África tenían un número de cupos garantizado de antemano. El número de clasificados de las otras confederaciones dependía de las repescas intercontinentales, que fueron jugadas entre los países mejor posicionados en sus respectivos continentes que aún no tenían clasificación directa. Las definiciones fueron: 4.º Lugar de CONCACAF vs. 5.º lugar de CONMEBOL Ganador del Repechaje de 5tos de AFC vs. Ganador de OFCEn total, 204 asociaciones de fútbol se inscribieron a la competición preliminar al 15 de marzo de 2007. 203 de las 207 existentes debían competir por los 31 cupos (incluyendo la selección sudafricana, que de todos modos participaba en los preliminares para jugar la Copa Africana de Naciones 2010). Luego se sumó la selección montenegrina, que se convirtió en el miembro número 208 de FIFA.En total se jugaron 848 partidos y se anotaron un total de 2337 goles, haciendo un promedio de 2.76 goles por partido.Sólo cuatro miembros asiáticos: Bután, Brunéi, Laos y las Filipinas no pudieron registrarse para la competencia.Después del cierre de las inscripciones, Bután fue incluido para las pre-clasificatorias asiáticas, mientras Brunéi y Laos fueron rechazados. El número final de equipos rompió el anterior récord de 199 en 2002. Sin embargo, cinco de aquellos equipos abandonaron sin jugar un sólo partido: Bután, República Centroafricana, Eritrea, Guam y Santo Tomé y Príncipe. Además, Papúa Nueva Guinea no pudo ingresar a los Juegos del Pacífico Sur (que albergaban las clasificatorias de Oceanía) y no formó parte en la clasificación.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Les qualifications pour la Coupe du Monde 2010 de football mettent aux prises 203 équipes nationales (sans compter l'Afrique du Sud qualifiée d'office car pays hôte) afin de qualifier 32 formations pour disputer la phase finale qui se jouera en Afrique du Sud.Les qualifications sont organisées par continents (ou confédérations continentales). De ce fait, la difficulté pour obtenir une place en phase finale dépend à la fois du niveau du jeu et du nombre de places réservées au continent d'origine d'une équipe. Les qualifications sur les continents où le football n'est pas un sport très répandu sont souvent considérées comme faciles pour les plus grandes équipes de ceux-ci.L'Afrique du Sud, pays organisateur, est qualifiée d'office comme le veut la règle habituelle. Il s'agit de la « récompenser » de ses efforts (infrastructures, accueil, organisation, etc.) en lui permettant de mobiliser tout le pays autour du projet, de s'assurer un succès auprès du public local et donc de mieux remplir les stades. Toutefois les éliminatoires de la confédération africaine étant communs avec ceux de la Coupe d'Afrique des nations de football 2010 , l'Afrique du Sud y participe.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup qualification competition was a series of tournaments organised by the six FIFA confederations. Each confederation — the AFC (Asia), CAF (Africa), CONCACAF (North, Central America and Caribbean), CONMEBOL (South America), OFC (Oceania), and UEFA (Europe) — was allocated a certain number of the 32 places at the tournament. A total of 205 teams entered the qualification competition, with South Africa, as the host, qualifying for the World Cup automatically. The first qualification matches were played on 25 August 2007 and qualification concluded on 18 November 2009. Overall, 2341 goals were scored over 852 matches.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Voor het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 in Zuid-Afrika moeten de landen zich kwalificeren. Het aantal beschikbare plaatsen voor elke confederatie hangt af van de sterkte van het continent en wordt als dusdanig verdeeld. Binnen elke confederatie spelen landen in aparte voorrondes voor de eindrondeplaatsen. Zuid-Afrika is het enige land dat rechtstreeks geplaatst is. Sinds 2006 moet ook de titelverdediger zich via de kwalificaties plaatsen.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_seeding</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The draw for the 2010 FIFA World Cup occurred in Cape Town, South Africa, on 4 December 2009, at 19:00 local time (UTC+2). In preparation for the draw, the qualified teams were seeded and organised into pots.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Cette page contient la liste de toutes les équipes et leurs joueurs ayant participé à la phase finale de la Coupe du Monde de football 2010 en Afrique du Sud. Le nombre de joueurs sélectionnés est limité à 23. Cependant, la FIFA a imposé aux sélectionneurs de dévoiler une première liste de 30 joueurs avant le 1er juin. La sélection définitive des 23 joueurs qui disputeront le Mondial en Afrique du Sud devra être présentée à la FIFA le 5 juin.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Para la XIX Copa Mundial de Fútbol, que se realizó en Sudáfrica entre el 11 de junio y el 11 de julio de 2010, 32 selecciones se clasificaron a la fase final. Las 32 selecciones fueron divididas en ocho grupos de cuatro integrantes. De cada grupo, los dos mejores equipos clasificaran a una segunda fase de eliminación directa, para determinar al campeón del torneo.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup was an international football tournament held in South Africa from 11 June until 11 July 2010. The 32 national teams involved in the tournament were required to register a squad of 23 players; only players in these squads were eligible to take part in the tournament.Before announcing their final squad for the tournament, teams were required to name a preliminary squad of 30 players by 11 May 2010, 30 days before the start of the tournament. With the exception of those involved in the 2010 UEFA Champions League Final, the players listed in the preliminary squad were then subjected to a mandatory rest period from 17 to 23 May 2010. The preliminary squad would then have to be cut to a final 23 by 1 June 2010 (midnight CET). Replacement of seriously injured players is permitted until 24 hours before the team in question's first World Cup game, though replacement players do not have to be drawn from the preliminary squad.Players marked (c) were named as captain for their national squad. Number of caps, players' club teams and players' age as of 11 June 2010: the tournament's opening day.There were only three national squads made up entirely of players from domestic clubs which were England, Italy and Germany. Nigeria was the only team with no players from domestic clubs.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_statistics</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">These are the statistics for the 2010 FIFA World Cup which took place in South Africa.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/20_Centres_for_2010</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">20 Centres for 2010 is an official campaign by FIFA coinciding with the 2010 World Cup in South Africa. Twenty centres will be built in twenty different cities across Africa. Education and public health will be the social services offered to youths, along with a soccer field children can use.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">El Jabulani fue el balón de fútbol oficial para la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010. El balón, fabricado por Adidas, fue desarrollado en la Universidad de Loughborough, en el Reino Unido, fue presentado oficialmente el 4 de diciembre de 2009 en Ciudad del Cabo, Sudafrica. La palabra «jabulani» significa ‘celebrar’ en zulú.En esa misma Copa Mundial se utilizó una versión del balón en color dorado llamado Jo'bulani, el balón oficial de la final del torneo. El nombre y color del esférico fueron elegidos como tributo a la ciudad de Johannesburgo, conocida también como Jo'burg o la "Ciudad de Oro". La final la disputaron las selecciones de Países Bajos y España, el 11 de julio de 2010, en la que España ganó por 0-1 con gol de Andrés Iniesta en la segunda parte de la prórroga. El Jo'bulani es el segundo balón que se produce exclusivamente para una final de la Copa Mundial tras el +Teamgeist Berlin de la Copa Mundial de la FIFA 2006.El balón fue empleado también en la Copa Mundial de Clubes de la FIFA 2009 en los Emiratos Árabes Unidos y una versión especial del balón, el Jabulani Angola, se utilizó en la Copa Africana de Naciones 2010. Este balón fue el mismo con el que se disputó el Torneo Clausura 2010 de Argentina, en la Major League Soccer 2010, en la 1. Bundesliga 2010/11 y en la Primera División de Portugal 2010/11.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Jabulani is de naam van de voetbal waarmee de wedstrijden op het WK 2010 in Zuid-Afrika werden gespeeld. In de finale heette de bal Jo'bulani. De Jo'bulani is goud gekleurd. Daarmee wordt verwezen naar Johannesburg (de stad van goud). De naam Jo'bulani is afgeleid van Jo'burg (waarmee Johannesburg wordt bedoeld), omdat de finale werd gespeeld in Johannesburg.De naam Jabulani komt uit het Zoeloe, de taal van de grootste etnische groepering in Zuid-Afrika. Jabulani betekent "feestelijk vieren". Fabrikant adidas heeft de bal elf kleuren gegeven, die symbool staan voor de elf officiële talen en elf Zuid-Afrikaanse stammen in Zuid-Afrika. Tevens staan de elf kleuren ook voor de elf spelers van een team, die op het veld staan.De bal werd enkele uren voor de WK-loting gepresenteerd als de "beste voetbal ooit". De bal zou ronder zijn dan andere ballen. De bal bestaat namelijk uit 8 vlakken van thermoplastisch polyurethaan. De Adidas Teamgeist, WK-bal van 2006, bestond uit 14 stukken.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Le Jabulani (en zoulou, être joyeux) est le ballon officiel de la coupe du monde de football 2010 fabriqué par Adidas. Il a été présenté le 4 décembre 2009 au Cap.Il a été conçu et développé spécialement pour cet événement qui s'est déroulé du 11 juin au 11 juillet 2010 en Afrique du Sud. Il arbore onze coloris uniques, en hommage aux 11 joueurs de chaque équipe, aux onze langues parlées en Afrique du Sud, et aux onze communautés sud-africaines qui seront hôtes de ce tournoi.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Jabulani is an Association football ball manufactured by Adidas. It was the official match ball for the 2010 FIFA World Cup.The ball is made from eight spherically moulded panels and has a textured surface intended to improve aerodynamics. Nevertheless, the ball received extensive criticism from players and coaches before and during the World Cup who said that the path of the ball through the air was unpredictable.The ball was consequently developed into the Adidas Tango 12 series of footballs.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Brazilië is één van de deelnemende landen op het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 dat in Zuid-Afrika wordt gespeeld. Het land neemt voor de negentiende keer in de geschiedenis deel. Hun laatste deelname was in 2006. Brazilië kwalificeerde zich als één van de vijf Zuid-Amerikaanse landen.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Cet article relate le parcours de l’équipe du Brésil de football lors de la Coupe du monde de football 2010 organisée en Afrique du Sud du 11 juin au 11 juillet 2010. C'est sa 19e participation à une Coupe du monde.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">La Selección de Brasil fue uno de los 32 equipos participantes de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010, que se realizó en Sudáfrica.Luego de superar la fase de grupos, en octavos de final eliminó a la selección de Chile por 3 a 0. En cuartos de final, la "verdeamarela" enfrentó a la selección de Países Bajos en Puerto Elizabeth, donde empezó ganando con gol de Robinho, pero en el segundo tiempo el seleccionado neerlandés, con dos goles de Wesley Sneijder, dio la vuelta al partido y dejó a Brasil eliminado del torneo. Debido a este resultado, Dunga renunció a su cargo de entrenador de la selección brasileña.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The following article concerns the performance of Brazil at the 2010 FIFA World Cup. Brazil won both their initial qualification group and their group during the tournament itself. They reached the quarter-final stages where they were knocked out by the eventual tournament runners-up, the Netherlands.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Crack_Money</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Crack Money is a South African business devoted to the sale, post-World Cup, of South African paraphernalia used during the World Cup in South Africa. The bulk of the articles are donated from former World Cup players, and 10% of the profits go towards exposing the extortion and manipulation that goes into FIFA player contracts controlled by player agents on the easily impressionable players in Africa and South America.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diski_Dance</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Diski dance is a dance composed of a series of choreographed football moves, named from different parts of the country, and was created for the 2010 FIFA World Cup as part of its advertising campaign. The creator of the Diski Dance is Wendy Ramokgadi, who died on Friday 27 May 2011.[citation needed] The moves are named in Tswana, Zulu, Sotho and English amongst others and include "Tsamaya", "Heel Extension Mkhari" and "Chester". The adverts were shown on CNN, BBC, Eurosport and SkySports amongst others. The motivation of the advert was to give soccer fans "a chance to learn the moves and "feel the rhythm of African football"".The Diski dance was featured in Matt Harding's 2010 "Where the Hell is Matt in South Africa?" video on YouTube, in preparation for the 2010 FIFA World Cup.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/FIFA_Fan_Fest</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The FIFA Fan Fests are public viewing events organized by FIFA and its partners which allow people to watch the FIFA World Cup with thousands of fans from all around the world. The Fan Fest first became part of the official program for the 2006 FIFA World Cup in Germany, following the huge success of unofficial Public Viewing events in South Korea during the 2002 tournament. It was a great success, leading FIFA to expand it to include several cities worldwide for the 2010 FIFA World Cup in South Africa. The locations are large enough to fit many thousands of people, and have gigantic LED displays which broadcast the matches live.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/July_2010_Kampala_attacks</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Le 11 juillet 2010, trois bombes ont explosé au milieu de foules qui regardaient la finale de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010 à Kampala, en Ouganda, dans deux endroits différents.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/July_2010_Kampala_attacks</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The July 2010 Kampala attacks were suicide bombings carried out against crowds watching a screening of 2010 FIFA World Cup Final match during the World Cup at two locations in Kampala, Uganda, on 11 July, 2010. The attacks left 74 dead and 70 injured. Al-Shabaab, a Sunni Islamist Somali militia believed to have ties to Al-Qaeda, has claimed responsibility for the attacks as retaliation for Ugandan support for AMISOM. This is al-Shabaab's first attack outside of Somalia.[citation needed]</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Larissa Mabel Riquelme Frutos, connue sous le nom de Larissa Riquelme, est un mannequin et une actrice paraguayenne née le 22 février 1985 à Asuncion au Paraguay. Elle est supportrice de l'équipe nationale du Paraguay et du club de Cerro Porteño. Depuis 2010, elle est le mannequin le mieux payé du Paraguay.</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>