<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_disciplinary_record</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">In the 2010 FIFA World Cup the main disciplinary action taken against players comes in the form of red and yellow cards.Any player picking up a red card is expelled from the pitch and automatically banned for his country's next match, whether via a straight red or second yellow. After a straight red card, FIFA will conduct a hearing and may extend this ban beyond one match. If the ban extends beyond the end of the World Cup finals (i.e.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_event_effects</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup is the 19th FIFA World Cup, the premier international association football tournament, being held in South Africa from 11 June to 11 July. It is the first time the finals of the tournament have been staged in an African host nation as South Africa were selected as hosts following a bidding in 2004. The impact of the event itself transcend those bound by its athletic aspect and appeal, and the socioeconomic aspects of the tournament are far reaching.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_knockout_stage</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La phase à élimination directe de la Coupe du monde de football 2010 oppose les 16 équipes qualifiées à l'issue du premier tour. Ces équipes se rencontrent dans des matchs à élimination directe à partir des huitièmes de finale.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_knockout_stage</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The knockout stage of the 2010 FIFA World Cup was the second and final stage of the World Cup, following the group stage. It began on 26 June with the round of 16 matches, and ended on 11 July with the final match of the tournament held at Soccer City, Johannesburg, in which Spain beat the Netherlands 1–0 after extra time to claim their first World Cup. The top two teams from each group (16 in total) advanced to the knockout stage to compete in a single-elimination style tournament.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_officials</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Officials for the 2010 FIFA World Cup are selected from a pool of 30 trios of referees and assistant referees announced by the association football governing body, FIFA, on 5 February 2010. The final cut was selected from a group of 38 referees revealed in October 2008, themselves whittled down from an initial group of 54 selected for the Refereeing Assistance Programme in 2007. From the quarter-finals onwards, the pool of referees was reduced to 19.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_opening_ceremony</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La cérémonie d'ouverture de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010 a eu lieu le 11 juin 2010 au stade Soccer City à Johannesburg, deux heures avant le match d'ouverture du tournoi. Elle a duré 40 minutes, et a inclus 1500 artistes, dont Thandiswa Mazwai, Timothy Moloi, Hugh Masekela, Khaled, Femi Kuti, Osibisa, R.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_opening_ceremony</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The opening ceremony took place on 11 June at the Soccer City stadium in Johannesburg, two hours before the opening match of the tournament. It lasted 40 minutes, and included 1500 performers, including Thandiswa Mazwai, Timothy Moloi, Hugh Masekela, Khaled, Femi Kuti, Osibisa, R.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">En el proceso de clasificación para la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 los equipos compitieron por 32 plazas en la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010, con una plaza destinada a su sede, Sudáfrica. Las seis confederaciones de la FIFA compartieron los 31 cupos restantes.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Les qualifications pour la Coupe du Monde 2010 de football mettent aux prises 203 équipes nationales (sans compter l'Afrique du Sud qualifiée d'office car pays hôte) afin de qualifier 32 formations pour disputer la phase finale qui se jouera en Afrique du Sud.Les qualifications sont organisées par continents (ou confédérations continentales).</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup qualification competition was a series of tournaments organised by the six FIFA confederations. Each confederation — the AFC (Asia), CAF (Africa), CONCACAF (North, Central America and Caribbean), CONMEBOL (South America), OFC (Oceania), and UEFA (Europe) — was allocated a certain number of the 32 places at the tournament. A total of 205 teams entered the qualification competition, with South Africa, as the host, qualifying for the World Cup automatically.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_qualification</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Voor het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 in Zuid-Afrika moeten de landen zich kwalificeren. Het aantal beschikbare plaatsen voor elke confederatie hangt af van de sterkte van het continent en wordt als dusdanig verdeeld. Binnen elke confederatie spelen landen in aparte voorrondes voor de eindrondeplaatsen. Zuid-Afrika is het enige land dat rechtstreeks geplaatst is. Sinds 2006 moet ook de titelverdediger zich via de kwalificaties plaatsen.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_seeding</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The draw for the 2010 FIFA World Cup occurred in Cape Town, South Africa, on 4 December 2009, at 19:00 local time (UTC+2). In preparation for the draw, the qualified teams were seeded and organised into pots.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Cette page contient la liste de toutes les équipes et leurs joueurs ayant participé à la phase finale de la Coupe du Monde de football 2010 en Afrique du Sud. Le nombre de joueurs sélectionnés est limité à 23. Cependant, la FIFA a imposé aux sélectionneurs de dévoiler une première liste de 30 joueurs avant le 1er juin. La sélection définitive des 23 joueurs qui disputeront le Mondial en Afrique du Sud devra être présentée à la FIFA le 5 juin.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Para la XIX Copa Mundial de Fútbol, que se realizó en Sudáfrica entre el 11 de junio y el 11 de julio de 2010, 32 selecciones se clasificaron a la fase final. Las 32 selecciones fueron divididas en ocho grupos de cuatro integrantes. De cada grupo, los dos mejores equipos clasificaran a una segunda fase de eliminación directa, para determinar al campeón del torneo.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_squads</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup was an international football tournament held in South Africa from 11 June until 11 July 2010. The 32 national teams involved in the tournament were required to register a squad of 23 players; only players in these squads were eligible to take part in the tournament.Before announcing their final squad for the tournament, teams were required to name a preliminary squad of 30 players by 11 May 2010, 30 days before the start of the tournament.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_statistics</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">These are the statistics for the 2010 FIFA World Cup which took place in South Africa.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/20_Centres_for_2010</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">20 Centres for 2010 is an official campaign by FIFA coinciding with the 2010 World Cup in South Africa. Twenty centres will be built in twenty different cities across Africa. Education and public health will be the social services offered to youths, along with a soccer field children can use.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">El Jabulani fue el balón de fútbol oficial para la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010. El balón, fabricado por Adidas, fue desarrollado en la Universidad de Loughborough, en el Reino Unido, fue presentado oficialmente el 4 de diciembre de 2009 en Ciudad del Cabo, Sudafrica. La palabra «jabulani» significa ‘celebrar’ en zulú.En esa misma Copa Mundial se utilizó una versión del balón en color dorado llamado Jo'bulani, el balón oficial de la final del torneo.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Jabulani is de naam van de voetbal waarmee de wedstrijden op het WK 2010 in Zuid-Afrika werden gespeeld. In de finale heette de bal Jo'bulani. De Jo'bulani is goud gekleurd. Daarmee wordt verwezen naar Johannesburg (de stad van goud). De naam Jo'bulani is afgeleid van Jo'burg (waarmee Johannesburg wordt bedoeld), omdat de finale werd gespeeld in Johannesburg.De naam Jabulani komt uit het Zoeloe, de taal van de grootste etnische groepering in Zuid-Afrika. Jabulani betekent "feestelijk vieren".</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Le Jabulani (en zoulou, être joyeux) est le ballon officiel de la coupe du monde de football 2010 fabriqué par Adidas. Il a été présenté le 4 décembre 2009 au Cap.Il a été conçu et développé spécialement pour cet événement qui s'est déroulé du 11 juin au 11 juillet 2010 en Afrique du Sud. Il arbore onze coloris uniques, en hommage aux 11 joueurs de chaque équipe, aux onze langues parlées en Afrique du Sud, et aux onze communautés sud-africaines qui seront hôtes de ce tournoi.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adidas_Jabulani</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Jabulani is an Association football ball manufactured by Adidas. It was the official match ball for the 2010 FIFA World Cup.The ball is made from eight spherically moulded panels and has a textured surface intended to improve aerodynamics.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Brazilië is één van de deelnemende landen op het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 dat in Zuid-Afrika wordt gespeeld. Het land neemt voor de negentiende keer in de geschiedenis deel. Hun laatste deelname was in 2006. Brazilië kwalificeerde zich als één van de vijf Zuid-Amerikaanse landen.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Cet article relate le parcours de l’équipe du Brésil de football lors de la Coupe du monde de football 2010 organisée en Afrique du Sud du 11 juin au 11 juillet 2010. C'est sa 19e participation à une Coupe du monde.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">La Selección de Brasil fue uno de los 32 equipos participantes de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010, que se realizó en Sudáfrica.Luego de superar la fase de grupos, en octavos de final eliminó a la selección de Chile por 3 a 0.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brazil_at_the_2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The following article concerns the performance of Brazil at the 2010 FIFA World Cup. Brazil won both their initial qualification group and their group during the tournament itself. They reached the quarter-final stages where they were knocked out by the eventual tournament runners-up, the Netherlands.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Crack_Money</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Crack Money is a South African business devoted to the sale, post-World Cup, of South African paraphernalia used during the World Cup in South Africa. The bulk of the articles are donated from former World Cup players, and 10% of the profits go towards exposing the extortion and manipulation that goes into FIFA player contracts controlled by player agents on the easily impressionable players in Africa and South America.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diski_Dance</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Diski dance is a dance composed of a series of choreographed football moves, named from different parts of the country, and was created for the 2010 FIFA World Cup as part of its advertising campaign. The creator of the Diski Dance is Wendy Ramokgadi, who died on Friday 27 May 2011.[citation needed] The moves are named in Tswana, Zulu, Sotho and English amongst others and include "Tsamaya", "Heel Extension Mkhari" and "Chester".</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/FIFA_Fan_Fest</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The FIFA Fan Fests are public viewing events organized by FIFA and its partners which allow people to watch the FIFA World Cup with thousands of fans from all around the world. The Fan Fest first became part of the official program for the 2006 FIFA World Cup in Germany, following the huge success of unofficial Public Viewing events in South Korea during the 2002 tournament.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/July_2010_Kampala_attacks</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Le 11 juillet 2010, trois bombes ont explosé au milieu de foules qui regardaient la finale de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010 à Kampala, en Ouganda, dans deux endroits différents.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/July_2010_Kampala_attacks</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The July 2010 Kampala attacks were suicide bombings carried out against crowds watching a screening of 2010 FIFA World Cup Final match during the World Cup at two locations in Kampala, Uganda, on 11 July, 2010. The attacks left 74 dead and 70 injured. Al-Shabaab, a Sunni Islamist Somali militia believed to have ties to Al-Qaeda, has claimed responsibility for the attacks as retaliation for Ugandan support for AMISOM. This is al-Shabaab's first attack outside of Somalia.[citation needed]</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Larissa Mabel Riquelme Frutos, connue sous le nom de Larissa Riquelme, est un mannequin et une actrice paraguayenne née le 22 février 1985 à Asuncion au Paraguay. Elle est supportrice de l'équipe nationale du Paraguay et du club de Cerro Porteño. Depuis 2010, elle est le mannequin le mieux payé du Paraguay.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Larissa Mabel Riquelme Frutos, usually known as Larissa Riquelme (born 22 February 1985) is a Paraguayan model and actress at the city theatre in the Paraguayan capital Asunción. She is one of the highest-paid models in Paraguay.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Larissa_Riquelme</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Larissa Riquelme (22 de febrero de 1985) es una modelo paraguaya. Se hizo conocida en el Mundial de fútbol 2010 en Sudáfrica donde fue apodada como La novia del mundial.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_controversies</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup generated various controversies, including some from before the tournament started. Most centred around refereeing.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_matches</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The 2010 FIFA World Cup was an international football tournament held in South Africa from 11 June until 11 July 2010. The 32 national teams involved in the tournament together played a total of 64 matches starting from the group stage matches and progressing to the knockout stage matches, with teams eliminated through the various progressive stages. Rest days were allocated during the various stages to allow players recovery during the tournament.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Listen Up! The Official 2010 FIFA World Cup Album is a collaboration by various artists, both local African and international. The album was released on May 31, 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Listen_Up!_The_Official_2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Album</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Listen Up! The Official 2010 FIFA World Cup Album is een verzamelalbum dat in 2010 verscheen als officieel album bij het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 in Zuid-Afrika dat georganiseerd werd door de FIFA.Het album bevat samenwerkingen tussen internationaal bekende artiesten met minder bekende Afrikaanse artiesten en Aziatische artiesten. Ook de officiële tune van het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal, Waka waka (This time for Africa), staat op het album.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">A lekarapa (plural makarapa) is a hand-cut and hand-painted hard hat worn by sports fans. They belong to the typical South African football fan's supporters gear, and are increasingly popular with fans of other sports. Sport fans spend hours to sculpt and paint their makarapa in the colours and emblem of their clubs or country. Besides the makarapa, fans also wear giant glasses or have shields with team slogans and logos.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">De Makarapa is een handgesneden en beschilderde helm. Het is een uit Zuid-Afrika afkomstige voetbalfanuitrusting, en het wordt steeds populairder bij fans van andere sporten. Sportfans spenderen uren om de makarapa uit te snijden en te beschilderen in de kleuren en logo's van hun club of land. Behalve de makarapa dragen fans ook meestal enorme brillen of schilden met slogans en logos. Het is algemeen geaccepteerd dat Alfred "Lux" Baloyi de uitvinder is van de Makarapa zoals we hem nu kennen.</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>