<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Makarapa</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Un makarapa est un casque de chantier à corne coupé et peint à la main qui est porté par les supporters de football sud-africains.Portail de l’Afrique du Sud Portail de l’Afrique du Sud Portail du football Portail du football</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Paul (pronunciación: /paʊl/) (nacido en enero de 2008 y muerto el 26 de octubre de 2010) fue un pulpo empleado como oráculo para predecir los resultados de la selección alemana de fútbol en competiciones internacionales, concretamente en la Eurocopa 2008 y en el Mundial de Fútbol 2010, donde también fue empleado para predecir otros resultados, acertando los ocho emparejamientos que se le propusieron.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Paul de Octopus (2008 in de Atlantische Oceaan in Weymouth, Dorset - 26 oktober 2010 in Oberhausen, Duitsland) was een in het Sea Life Centre te Oberhausen, Duitsland woonachtige achtarm, die in de zomer van 2010 dankzij de internationale pers grote bekendheid verwierf als voorspeller van voetbaluitslagen van vooral het Duitse voetbalelftal tijdens het Wereldkampioenschap Voetbal in Zuid-Afrika.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Paul le poulpe ou Paul la pieuvre, surnommé « l’oracle d’Oberhausen » (Weymouth, 26 janvier 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 octobre 2010) est une pieuvre commune mâle maintenue en captivité à l’aquarium Sea Life d’Oberhausen en Allemagne. Paul est renommé pour le spectacle de ses prédictions du résultat des matchs de l’équipe d'Allemagne de football lors du Championnat d’Europe 2008 et de la Coupe du monde 2010, dont il a également désigné le vainqueur.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul the Octopus (hatched in 2008, died October 2010) was a common octopus living in a tank at a Sea Life Centre in Oberhausen, Germany, who was used as an animal oracle to predict the results of football matches, usually international matches in which Germany was playing.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poor_People's_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The Poor People's World Cup was an event organised by a South African social movement in response to the 2010 FIFA World Cup in South Africa.The event was created by the Western Cape Anti-Eviction Campaign who believed that the World Cup has had a negative impact on poor communities in Cape Town, via evictions, relocations, and not being allowed to trade near the new football stadiums.The event consisted of 36 teams from poor South African communities, and each represents an official World Cup country. </sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Santo,_Sam_and_Ed's_Cup_Fever!</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Santo, Sam and Ed's Cup Fever! was an association football themed comedy television show in Australia on SBS. The nightly panel-style show was produced by Working Dog Productions and aired for the duration of the 2010 FIFA World Cup. The show was hosted by Santo Cilauro, Sam Pang and Ed Kavalee, with Rob Sitch making several guest appearances. Segments included Cup Update (a discussion of the previous day's World Cup matches), an interview with a special guest and various comedy sketches.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Een vuvuzela is een blaasinstrument dat vooral in Zuid-Afrika populair is onder voetbalfans en dat in 2010, naar aanleiding van het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, ook in veel andere landen bekend is geworden.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La vuvuzela, appelée lepatata en setswana, parfois francisée en vouvouzela, est une corne d'environ 70 centimètres de long, popularisée dans les années 1990 par les supporters des deux clubs de Soweto en Afrique du Sud : les Kaizer Chiefs (équipés du modèle jaune) et les Orlando Pirates (équipés du modèle noir et blanc).</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The vuvuzela /vuːvuːˈzɛlə/, also known as lepatata Mambu (its Tswana name), is a plastic horn, about 65 centimetres (2 ft) long, which produces a loud monotone note, typically around B♭ 3 (the B♭ below middle C). Some models are made in two parts to facilitate storage, and this design also allows pitch variation. Many types of vuvuzela, made by several manufacturers, may produce various intensity and frequency outputs.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Una vuvuzela (en zulú, también conocida como lepatata en setsuana) es una especie de trompeta larga o corneta hecha de material plástico, utilizada por los aficionados para animar a sus equipos o clubes deportivos. Ha sido usada desde los años 60 en diferentes estadios del mundo sin ningún nombre específico, pero debe su nombre africano a que fue popularizada en tiempos de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 en Sudáfrica.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/We're_with_You</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">"We're With You" is a Korean language song, and the third digital single by South Korean girl group Kara. It was part of SBS's 2010 FIFA World Cup campaign to cheer for the South Korean team in South Africa. The song was released on May 3, 2010. The first physical release of the song was on the Tour edition of the group's second Japanese album "Super Girl", released on April 11, 2012.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Write_the_Future</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Write the Future is an advert made by Nike football for the 2010 World Cup and directed by Mexican filmmaker Alejandro González Iñárritu for the UK based production company, Independent Films Limited. The full version is over three minutes in length and features football players Didier Drogba, Fabio Cannavaro, Wayne Rooney, Franck Ribéry, Ronaldinho, and Cristiano Ronaldo as its main players.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Zakumi (16 juni 1994) is de mascotte van de Confederations Cup 2009 en het Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, dat werd gehouden in Zuid-Afrika.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Zakumi (concebido 16 de Junio de 1994, imagen física de 16 años) fue la mascota oficial de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 que se realizó en Sudáfrica. Se trata de un leopardo africano antropomorfo con el pelo verde, diseñado por Andries Odendaal, un diseñador sudafricano originario de Ciudad del Cabo. Fue presentado el 22 de septiembre de 2008.Su nombre viene de “ZA” (el código ISO para Sudáfrica) y “kumi”, que significa diez en varias lenguas africanas.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Zakumi est la mascotte officielle pour la Coupe du monde de football de 2010. C'est un léopard aux cheveux verts né le 16 juin 1994, qui a été présenté le 22 septembre 2008. Son nom vient de « ZA », l'abréviation internationale pour l'Afrique du Sud, et « kumi », un mot qui signifie « dix » dans diverses langues africaines.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Zakumi</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Zakumi the Leopard (born (1994-06-16) 16 June 1994) was the Official Mascot for the 2010 FIFA World Cup. He is a cheerful, sporty anthropomorphized leopard with green hair, presented on 22 September 2008. His name comes from "ZA", the ISO 3166-1 alpha-2 code for South Africa, and "kumi", a word that means ten in several African languages, referencing the year 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Coupe du monde de football de 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup Final</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Final de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Finale de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Final</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Finale wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_A</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup Group A</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_A</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Groupe A de la Coupe du monde de football 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_A</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 groep A</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_B</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup Group B</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_B</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Groupe B de la Coupe du monde de football 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_B</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 groep B</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_C</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup Group C</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_C</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Groupe C de la Coupe du monde de football 2010</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_C</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010 groep C</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/2010_FIFA_World_Cup_Group_D</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">2010 FIFA World Cup Group D</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>