<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Individual_octopuses</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:UEFA_Euro_2008</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2010_animal_deaths</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/depiction</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Oktopus-Orakel_Paul_mit_Schuh.JPG</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_the_Octopus?oldid=606129546</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ar">الأخطبوط بول (باللاتينية: Paul) (ولد سنة 2008، نفق في 26 أكتوبر 2010) هو أخطبوط لقى اهتمامًا إعلاميًا كبيرًا على المستوى العالمي نظرًا لتوقعه الصحيح للفائزين في مباريات كرة القدم، خصوصًا التي يكون منتخب ألمانيا لكرة القدم طرفًا فيها. ولد في إنجلترا، ثم نقل إلى أحواض الحياة البحرية بمدينة أوبرهاوزن الألمانية.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="it">Il polpo Paul (Isola d'Elba o Weymouth, gennaio 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 ottobre 2010) (in tedesco Paul der Krake) era un polpo comune che viveva in un acquario pubblico presso il centro di vita marina di Oberhausen, in Germania, e che ha conosciuto una certa notorietà internazionale in occasione dei Mondiali di calcio del 2010 quando fu utilizzato per tentare di "predire" i risultati delle partite di calcio in cui era coinvolta la Nazionale di calcio tedesca.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Paul le poulpe ou Paul la pieuvre, surnommé « l’oracle d’Oberhausen » (Weymouth, 26 janvier 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 octobre 2010) est une pieuvre commune mâle maintenue en captivité à l’aquarium Sea Life d’Oberhausen en Allemagne. Paul est renommé pour le spectacle de ses prédictions du résultat des matchs de l’équipe d'Allemagne de football lors du Championnat d’Europe 2008 et de la Coupe du monde 2010, dont il a également désigné le vainqueur.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">パウル（ドイツ語: Paul der Krake、Oktopus-Orakel、2008年1月 - 2010年10月26日）は、かつてドイツ・オーバーハウゼンの水族館シー・ライフで飼育されていたマダコ。サッカードイツ代表の国際試合の結果を予言し、EURO2008では全6試合のうち4試合を的中、W杯南アフリカ大会ではドイツ代表の7試合に決勝戦を加えた計8試合の勝敗を全て的中させ、国際的な名声を得た。なお、ドイツ語の「au」は日本人には「アウ」よりも「アオ」という発音に近く聞こえ、日本放送協会（NHK）ではパオルと表記している。また、日本語圏のメディアでは、「パウル君」と表記されることが一般的である。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Paul de Octopus (2008 in de Atlantische Oceaan in Weymouth, Dorset - 26 oktober 2010 in Oberhausen, Duitsland) was een in het Sea Life Centre te Oberhausen, Duitsland woonachtige achtarm, die in de zomer van 2010 dankzij de internationale pers grote bekendheid verwierf als voorspeller van voetbaluitslagen van vooral het Duitse voetbalelftal tijdens het Wereldkampioenschap Voetbal in Zuid-Afrika.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="zh">八爪魚保羅（德语：Paul Oktopus；2008年1月26日－2010年10月26日）是德國奧伯豪森（Oberhausen）一個水族館的一隻普通八爪魚（学名：Octopus vulgaris）。據稱這隻八爪魚能準確預測德國國家足球隊的比賽結果，因而有「德國神算子」、「章魚哥」、「保罗哥」、「章魚帝」、「预测帝」之稱。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pt">Paul, o polvo (Ilha de Elba, 26 de janeiro de 2008 — Oberhausen, 26 de outubro de 2010) foi um molusco da espécie Octopus vulgaris residente no Aquário Marinho (Sea Life Centre) de Oberhausen, na Alemanha, que se tornou conhecido no mundo inteiro por "prever" — segundo se tem usado interpretar e dizer — corretamente os resultados da Seleção Alemã no Mundial de 2010, na África do Sul.Antes dos jogos, Paul era colocado perante duas caixas com mexilhões, que é o alimento da espécie: uma com a bandeira alemã, outra com a bandeira da seleção oponente. </sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">Paul (* 26. Januar 2008 im Atlantischen Ozean bei Weymouth, Dorset; † 26. Oktober 2010 im Sea Life Centre, Oberhausen) war ein Krake, der als Orakeltier für die „Vorhersage“ von Spielergebnissen bei internationalen Fußballturnieren bekannt wurde.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ru">Осьмино́г Па́уль (нем. Paul; январь 2008, Уэймут, Дорсет, Англия — 26 октября 2010, Оберхаузен, Германия), в Германии также известен как «Осьминог-оракул» (нем. Oktopus-Orakel) — осьминог мужского пола вида осьминог обыкновенный (Octopus vulgaris), получивший известность благодаря предполагаемой способности угадывать исходы матчей с участием футбольной сборной Германии. Обитал в океанариуме «Центр морской жизни» в Оберхаузене (Германия).</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul the Octopus (hatched in 2008, died October 2010) was a common octopus living in a tank at a Sea Life Centre in Oberhausen, Germany, who was used as an animal oracle to predict the results of football matches, usually international matches in which Germany was playing.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pl">Paul (złapany 2008 w Weymouth, padł 26 października 2010 w Oberhausen) – ośmiornica zwyczajna (Octopus vulgaris) żyjąca w akwarium Sea Life Centre w Oberhausen. Zwierzę było w 2008 i 2010 używane do typowania wyników meczów reprezentacji Niemiec w piłce nożnej. Niezwykła skuteczność typów Paula sprawiła, że stał się on popularny na całym świecie.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Paul (pronunciación: /paʊl/) (nacido en enero de 2008 y muerto el 26 de octubre de 2010) fue un pulpo empleado como oráculo para predecir los resultados de la selección alemana de fútbol en competiciones internacionales, concretamente en la Eurocopa 2008 y en el Mundial de Fútbol 2010, donde también fue empleado para predecir otros resultados, acertando los ocho emparejamientos que se le propusieron.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/species</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Octopus vulgaris</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/isPrimaryTopicOf</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/image</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Serbia .svg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/image</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Germany.svg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/image</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Spain.svg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/hasPhotoCollection</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://wifo5-03.informatik.uni-mannheim.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/caption</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Serbia</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/caption</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul in his tank, next to a football boot with the German flag colours</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/caption</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Germany</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/caption</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Spain</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/name</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul the Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/width</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">100</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/thumbnail</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Oktopus-Orakel_Paul_mit_Schuh.JPG?width=300</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul the Octopus (hatched in 2008, died October 2010) was a common octopus living in a tank at a Sea Life Centre in Oberhausen, Germany, who was used as an animal oracle to predict the results of football matches, usually international matches in which Germany was playing. He came to worldwide attention with his accurate predictions in the 2010 World Cup.During a divination, Paul was presented with two boxes containing food, each marked with the flag of a national football team in an upcoming match. He chose the box with the flag of the winning team in several of Germany's six Euro 2008 matches, and all seven of their matches in the 2010 World Cup—with Germany's third place playoff win over Uruguay on 10 July. His success rate rose to 85 percent, with 11 out of 13 matches correctly predicted. He predicted a win for Spain against the Netherlands in the World Cup final on 11 July by eating the mussel in the box with the Spanish flag on it.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">パウル（ドイツ語: Paul der Krake、Oktopus-Orakel、2008年1月 - 2010年10月26日）は、かつてドイツ・オーバーハウゼンの水族館シー・ライフで飼育されていたマダコ。サッカードイツ代表の国際試合の結果を予言し、EURO2008では全6試合のうち4試合を的中、W杯南アフリカ大会ではドイツ代表の7試合に決勝戦を加えた計8試合の勝敗を全て的中させ、国際的な名声を得た。なお、ドイツ語の「au」は日本人には「アウ」よりも「アオ」という発音に近く聞こえ、日本放送協会（NHK）ではパオルと表記している。また、日本語圏のメディアでは、「パウル君」と表記されることが一般的である。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">Paul le poulpe ou Paul la pieuvre, surnommé « l’oracle d’Oberhausen » (Weymouth, 26 janvier 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 octobre 2010) est une pieuvre commune mâle maintenue en captivité à l’aquarium Sea Life d’Oberhausen en Allemagne. Paul est renommé pour le spectacle de ses prédictions du résultat des matchs de l’équipe d'Allemagne de football lors du Championnat d’Europe 2008 et de la Coupe du monde 2010, dont il a également désigné le vainqueur. Paul le poulpe faisait connaître ses choix en ouvrant une boîte aux couleurs de l'équipe gagnante. Sur quatorze prédictions au total, douze se sont révélées exactes, dont toutes celles émises au cours de la Coupe du Monde 2010 qui l'aura fait accéder à la postérité.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Paul de Octopus (2008 in de Atlantische Oceaan in Weymouth, Dorset - 26 oktober 2010 in Oberhausen, Duitsland) was een in het Sea Life Centre te Oberhausen, Duitsland woonachtige achtarm, die in de zomer van 2010 dankzij de internationale pers grote bekendheid verwierf als voorspeller van voetbaluitslagen van vooral het Duitse voetbalelftal tijdens het Wereldkampioenschap Voetbal in Zuid-Afrika. Hij wist de uitslag van alle zeven wedstrijden van het Duitse team juist te voorspellen en bovendien de uitslag van de finale van Nederland tegen Spanje. Ook tijdens het Europees kampioenschap voetbal 2008 was hij reeds actief. Hij maakte toen echter twee fouten, waaronder de voorspelling van de winnaar van de finale, waar hij ten onrechte Duitsland in plaats van Spanje als winnaar aanwees. Paul was overigens niet het enige dier dat voorspellingen deed over finale van het WK 2010.Daags na de finale van het wereldkampioenschap 2010 heeft het Sealife Aquarium in Oberhausen bekendgemaakt dat Paul de Octopus als voorspeller met pensioen is gegaan. Ten tijde van zijn pensionering was hij reeds vrij oud voor een octopus, namelijk tweeënhalf jaar. Hij was 50 centimeter lang.Het dorp Carballiño in de Noord-Spaanse regio Galicië, dat 14.000 inwoners telt, heeft Paul op 13 juli 2010 tot ereburger uitgeroepen. De onderscheiding, een doorzichtige urn met het wapen van Carballiño werd persoonlijk door burgemeester Carlos Montes in Oberhausen aan Paul overhandigd. Carlos Montes had het Duitse Sea Life Centre 35.000 euro geboden om Paul over te nemen en als toeristenlokkertje in Carballiño te plaatsen. Paul bleef gewoon in zijn eigen aquarium te Oberhausen waar hij op 26 oktober 2010 dood werd aangetroffen door zijn verzorgers.Begin 2011 werd bekendgemaakt dat er een gedenkplaats zou komen voor Paul de Octopus.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Paul (pronunciación: /paʊl/) (nacido en enero de 2008 y muerto el 26 de octubre de 2010) fue un pulpo empleado como oráculo para predecir los resultados de la selección alemana de fútbol en competiciones internacionales, concretamente en la Eurocopa 2008 y en el Mundial de Fútbol 2010, donde también fue empleado para predecir otros resultados, acertando los ocho emparejamientos que se le propusieron. Debido a la notable trascendencia mediática que le otorgó este hecho, surgieron en ciertos países algunos nombres con los que fue denominado y que hacían referencia a sus supuestas facultades adivinatorias; así en alemán fue conocido como das Krakenorakel y en inglés como the psychic octopus, expresiones que en lengua española significan «pulpo oráculo» y «pulpo médium», respectivamente. Después del campeonato mundial de fútbol, sus cuidadores comunicaron que no volvería a realizar más pronósticos.A pesar de haber nacido en el Sea Life Centre de Weymouth, una localidad del sur de Inglaterra, vivió en las instalaciones del Sea Life Centre en Oberhausen, Alemania. Su nombre fue tomado del título de un poema del escritor alemán de literatura infantil Boy Lornsen, titulado «Der Tintenfisch Paul Oktopus» (El calamar Paul, el pulpo). Según el director del acuario, Paul demostró pronto una destacada inteligencia, y afirmó que su peculiar forma de mirar a los visitantes llevó a sus cuidadores a intentar comprobar su talento.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="zh">八爪魚保羅（德语：Paul Oktopus；2008年1月26日－2010年10月26日）是德國奧伯豪森（Oberhausen）一個水族館的一隻普通八爪魚（学名：Octopus vulgaris）。據稱這隻八爪魚能準確預測德國國家足球隊的比賽結果，因而有「德國神算子」、「章魚哥」、「保罗哥」、「章魚帝」、「预测帝」之稱。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pt">Paul, o polvo (Ilha de Elba, 26 de janeiro de 2008 — Oberhausen, 26 de outubro de 2010) foi um molusco da espécie Octopus vulgaris residente no Aquário Marinho (Sea Life Centre) de Oberhausen, na Alemanha, que se tornou conhecido no mundo inteiro por "prever" — segundo se tem usado interpretar e dizer — corretamente os resultados da Seleção Alemã no Mundial de 2010, na África do Sul.Antes dos jogos, Paul era colocado perante duas caixas com mexilhões, que é o alimento da espécie: uma com a bandeira alemã, outra com a bandeira da seleção oponente. A caixa escolhida para se alimentar era interpretada como uma previsão do vencedor do confronto.Na Copa do Mundo de 2010, Paul previu a queda da seleção Alemã nas semifinais e a conquista do terceiro lugar, tendo acertado todos os palpites da campanha (7 jogos). A previsão sobre a derrota para a Espanha foi seguida por cerca de 20 estações de televisão internacionais.Paul também acertou o palpite para a grande final, entre Espanha e Holanda: novamente apostou nos espanhóis, que ficaram com seu primeiro título mundial.O polvo Paul foi ainda alvo de negócios entre o seu aquário e o de Madrid sendo feita uma oferta de vários milhares de euros mas o aquário de Oberhausen recusou sempre as propostas.A polémica organização americana de defesa dos direitos animais, PETA, reclamou a libertação do polvo nas águas do Sul de França.Paul foi pescado em águas italianas, próximo a ilha de Elba e adestrado por Verena Bartsch, uma jovem alemã de 22 anos, que testemunhou ser o molusco marinho de nacionalidade italiana.Paul morreu de causas naturais em 26 de outubro de 2010 enquanto descansava.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="it">Il polpo Paul (Isola d'Elba o Weymouth, gennaio 2008 - Oberhausen, 26 ottobre 2010) (in tedesco Paul der Krake) era un polpo comune che viveva in un acquario pubblico presso il centro di vita marina di Oberhausen, in Germania, e che ha conosciuto una certa notorietà internazionale in occasione dei Mondiali di calcio del 2010 quando fu utilizzato per tentare di "predire" i risultati delle partite di calcio in cui era coinvolta la Nazionale di calcio tedesca. Ad esse si aggiunse anche quella della finale non disputata dalla Germania; le "previsioni" in quell'occasione si rivelarono tutte corrette. Paul è morto nella notte tra il 25 e il 26 ottobre 2010 nello stesso Sea Life Center di Oberhausen, in Germania.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ar">الأخطبوط بول (باللاتينية: Paul) (ولد سنة 2008، نفق في 26 أكتوبر 2010) هو أخطبوط لقى اهتمامًا إعلاميًا كبيرًا على المستوى العالمي نظرًا لتوقعه الصحيح للفائزين في مباريات كرة القدم، خصوصًا التي يكون منتخب ألمانيا لكرة القدم طرفًا فيها. ولد في إنجلترا، ثم نقل إلى أحواض الحياة البحرية بمدينة أوبرهاوزن الألمانية.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pl">Paul (złapany 2008 w Weymouth, padł 26 października 2010 w Oberhausen) – ośmiornica zwyczajna (Octopus vulgaris) żyjąca w akwarium Sea Life Centre w Oberhausen. Zwierzę było w 2008 i 2010 używane do typowania wyników meczów reprezentacji Niemiec w piłce nożnej. Niezwykła skuteczność typów Paula sprawiła, że stał się on popularny na całym świecie.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">Paul (* 26. Januar 2008 im Atlantischen Ozean bei Weymouth, Dorset; † 26. Oktober 2010 im Sea Life Centre, Oberhausen) war ein Krake, der als Orakeltier für die „Vorhersage“ von Spielergebnissen bei internationalen Fußballturnieren bekannt wurde. Er lebte in dem Großaquarium Sea Life Centre im nordrhein-westfälischen Oberhausen.Besondere Medienbekanntheit erreichte Paul, als er während der Fußball-Weltmeisterschaft 2010 als Kraken-Orakel (auch: Oktopus-Orakel, Tentakel-Orakel oder Okrakel) den Ausgang aller Spiele mit deutscher Beteiligung sowie das Endspiel der WM korrekt „voraussagte“. Nach der Weltmeisterschaft wurde Paul nicht mehr „befragt“.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ru">Осьмино́г Па́уль (нем. Paul; январь 2008, Уэймут, Дорсет, Англия — 26 октября 2010, Оберхаузен, Германия), в Германии также известен как «Осьминог-оракул» (нем. Oktopus-Orakel) — осьминог мужского пола вида осьминог обыкновенный (Octopus vulgaris), получивший известность благодаря предполагаемой способности угадывать исходы матчей с участием футбольной сборной Германии. Обитал в океанариуме «Центр морской жизни» в Оберхаузене (Германия). 20 января 2011 года на территории океанариума открыт памятник — осьминог на футбольном мяче, внутри которого находится прах Пауля.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageID</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">27973567</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageRevisionID</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">606129546</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/namedafter</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">A poem by Boy Lornsen, Der Tintenfisch Paul Oktopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/birthplace</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Weymouth,_Dorset</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/othername</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Paul Oktopus, Paul der Krake</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/direction</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">vertical</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/footer</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flags picked by Paul</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/known</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Predicting results of Germany's football matches</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/occupation</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Exhibit</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/owner</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sea_Life_Centres</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/alt</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Spain: A horizontal tricolour of red, yellow and red, the yellow stripe being twice the size of each red stripe and containing the coat of arms</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/alt</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Serbia: A horizontal tricolour of red, blue. and white, with the lesser coat of arms</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/alt</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Flag of Germany: A horizontal tricolour of black, red and gold</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/gender</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Male</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/birthdate</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">2008</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_II</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageDisambiguates</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ar.dbpedia.org/resource/الأخطبوط_بول</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://az.dbpedia.org/resource/İlbiz_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://be.dbpedia.org/resource/Васьміног_Паўль</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://be_x_old.dbpedia.org/resource/Паўль_(васьміног)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://bg.dbpedia.org/resource/Паул_(октопод)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://bn.dbpedia.org/resource/পল_(অক্টোপাস)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://br.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_ar_souae</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ca.dbpedia.org/resource/Polp_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://da.dbpedia.org/resource/Blæksprutten_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://eo.dbpedia.org/resource/Paŭlo_(polpo)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://et.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_(kaheksajalg)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://fa.dbpedia.org/resource/پاول_(هشت‌پا)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://fi.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_(mustekala)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://gl.dbpedia.org/resource/Polbo_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://he.dbpedia.org/resource/פול_התמנון</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://hu.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_(polip)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://jv.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_si_Gurita</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://lv.dbpedia.org/resource/Astoņkājis_Pols</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ml.dbpedia.org/resource/പോൾ_നീരാളി</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ms.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_si_sotong_peramal</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://no.dbpedia.org/resource/Blekkspruten_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ro.dbpedia.org/resource/Caracatița_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Пауль_(осьминог)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sh.dbpedia.org/resource/Oktopod_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://simple.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sq.dbpedia.org/resource/Oktapodi_Pol</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sr.dbpedia.org/resource/Хоботница_Паул</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sv.dbpedia.org/resource/Bläckfisken_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ta.dbpedia.org/resource/பால்_ஆக்டோபஸ்</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://th.dbpedia.org/resource/หมึกพอล</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://tl.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_Pugita</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://tr.dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_(ahtapot)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://uk.dbpedia.org/resource/Восьминіг_Пауль</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://vi.dbpedia.org/resource/Bạch_tuộc_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://war.dbpedia.org/resource/Kugita_Paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://zh.dbpedia.org/resource/章鱼保罗</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://zh_yue.dbpedia.org/resource/八爪魚保羅</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/primaryTopic</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Octopus_(disambiguation)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageDisambiguates</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Octopus_paul</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageRedirects</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Oracle_octopus</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageRedirects</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_(Octopus)</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageRedirects</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paul_the_Octopus</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>