<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><sem:triples xmlns:sem="http://marklogic.com/semantics"><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="zh">呜呜祖拉</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_football_culture</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Zulu_words_and_phrases</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1965_introductions</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Brass_instruments</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_football_controversies</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2010_FIFA_World_Cup</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:South_African_English</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://purl.org/dc/terms/subject</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Natural_horns</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/depiction</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Vuvuzela_red.jpg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vuvuzela?oldid=595415476</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La vuvuzela, appelée lepatata en setswana, parfois francisée en vouvouzela, est une corne d'environ 70 centimètres de long, popularisée dans les années 1990 par les supporters des deux clubs de Soweto en Afrique du Sud : les Kaizer Chiefs (équipés du modèle jaune) et les Orlando Pirates (équipés du modèle noir et blanc).</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Een vuvuzela is een blaasinstrument dat vooral in Zuid-Afrika populair is onder voetbalfans en dat in 2010, naar aanleiding van het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, ook in veel andere landen bekend is geworden.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="it">La vuvuzela, chiamata anche lepatata (in lingua tswana), è una trombetta ad aria, solitamente di plastica, lunga circa 65 cm, brevettata da Neil Van Schalkwyk.La vuvuzela produce un suono potente, monocorde, tipicamente vicino al Si♭.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="zh">呜呜祖拉（Vuvuzela，在茨瓦纳语中又被称为“lepatata”），又称呜呜泽拉、巫巫宰拉、巫巫塞拉、呜呜赛拉、巫巫兹拉、嗚嗚聲喇、呼呼塞拉、瓦瓦祖拉、嗚嗚些拿、嗚嗚茲拉、烏烏茲拉、非洲笛，長喇叭或嗚嗚號，是一种长约一米的号角。南非的球迷常在足球比赛上吹奏，吹响呜呜祖拉需要一定的唇部技巧和肺活量；吹奏呜呜祖拉时，會發出單調聲音(B♭)，类似于雾笛或大象的声音。呜呜祖拉的使用已引起爭議。它發出的聲音可能會對聽力構成永久損害，同時也會引起一些安全問題，例如會令在球場的觀眾無法聽見緊急疏散的宣佈，以及比咳嗽和吶喊較易導致感冒及流感病毒的大規模傳播。2010年世界盃足球賽部份的實況播音員把呜呜祖拉的聲音稱為「令人烦躁的」、「一群嘈吵的大象的狂奔」、「一群極喧鬧的蝗蟲」、「將被宰殺的山羊叫聲」和「一個充滿憤怒的蜜蜂的巨大蜂箱」。這種樂器響度可以達到127分貝 對未作保護的人耳有極大傷害。2010年6月14日一種新型的呜呜祖拉問世，聲稱通過調整唇片使其音量下降了20分貝。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pt">A vuvuzela (conhecida no Brasil como corneta ou cornetão e em partes de Moçambique como xipalapala) é um aerofone cilíndrico de cerca de um metro de comprimento, usada por torcedores em jogos de futebol. As vuvuzelas ganharam forte exposição na mídia devido à Copa do Mundo 2010 realizada na África do Sul e a função sonora que exercem para comemorar gols ou durante a partida.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The vuvuzela /vuːvuːˈzɛlə/, also known as lepatata Mambu (its Tswana name), is a plastic horn, about 65 centimetres (2 ft) long, which produces a loud monotone note, typically around B♭ 3 (the B♭ below middle C). Some models are made in two parts to facilitate storage, and this design also allows pitch variation. Many types of vuvuzela, made by several manufacturers, may produce various intensity and frequency outputs.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">Die Vuvuzela [vuvuˈzɛla] (Zulu) (auf Setswana manchmal auch Lepatata genannt) ist ein Blasinstrument und gilt als ein Symbol des südafrikanischen Fußballs.Aufgrund ihrer Tonerzeugung gehört die Vuvuzela zu den Blechblasinstrumenten. Das ursprünglich aus Blech, inzwischen allerdings meist aus Kunststoff gefertigte Instrument besteht aus einer konischen, bis zu einem Meter langen Röhre, die an ihrem engen Ende mit einem integrierten Trichtermundstück versehen ist.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Una vuvuzela (en zulú, también conocida como lepatata en setsuana) es una especie de trompeta larga o corneta hecha de material plástico, utilizada por los aficionados para animar a sus equipos o clubes deportivos. Ha sido usada desde los años 60 en diferentes estadios del mundo sin ningún nombre específico, pero debe su nombre africano a que fue popularizada en tiempos de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 en Sudáfrica.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pl">Wuwuzela (vuvuzela, także "lepatata") – aerofon ustnikowy używany przez kibiców piłki nożnej w Afryce. Wydaje głośny dźwięk (osiągający przy wylocie wuwuzeli natężenie 122–131 dB(A)) mający przypominać ryczenie słonia. Pierwotnie jej egzemplarze wykonywano z puszek po konserwach, obecnie są produkowane głównie z tworzyw sztucznych.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ar">فوفوزيلا (Vuvuzela كما تلفظ حسب لغة زولو) عبارة عن آلة نفخ تستخدم عادة في ملاعب كرة القدم في جنوب أفريقيا. تسمى أيضاً ليباتاتا Lepatata حسب لغة سيتسوانا.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ru">Вувузе́ла (зулу vuvuzela, «делать шум»), также известен как лепатата (lepatata)) — рожок длиной до метра, ставший широко известным во время чемпионата мира по футболу 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">ブブゼラ (Vuvuzela) は、南アフリカの楽器。ツワナ語ではレパタタ (lepatata) とも呼ばれる。“ブブセラ”と表記するのは間違い。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/isPrimaryTopicOf</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/hasPhotoCollection</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://wifo5-03.informatik.uni-mannheim.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/background</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">brass</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/name</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/thumbnail</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Vuvuzela_red.jpg?width=300</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ru">Вувузе́ла (зулу vuvuzela, «делать шум»), также известен как лепатата (lepatata)) — рожок длиной до метра, ставший широко известным во время чемпионата мира по футболу 2010.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="it">La vuvuzela, chiamata anche lepatata (in lingua tswana), è una trombetta ad aria, solitamente di plastica, lunga circa 65 cm, brevettata da Neil Van Schalkwyk.La vuvuzela produce un suono potente, monocorde, tipicamente vicino al Si♭. Essa è comunemente usata in Sudafrica dai tifosi che assistono alle partite di calcio ed è per questo divenuta una sorta di simbolo del calcio stesso in quel paese, anche in virtù della falsa convinzione, che fu sostenuta anche dalla presidenza della FIFA, che la vuvuzela fosse nata come una riproduzione in plastica del corno di antilope, che in Sudafrica era usato nella tradizione tribale.L'origine del suo nome è controversa: potrebbe infatti essere un termine onomatopeico in lingua zulu che significa "fare vuvu", in riferimento al suono emesso dallo strumento, oppure derivare da un termine gergale dei sobborghi che significa "doccia", in riferimento alla sua forma.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pl">Wuwuzela (vuvuzela, także "lepatata") – aerofon ustnikowy używany przez kibiców piłki nożnej w Afryce. Wydaje głośny dźwięk (osiągający przy wylocie wuwuzeli natężenie 122–131 dB(A)) mający przypominać ryczenie słonia. Pierwotnie jej egzemplarze wykonywano z puszek po konserwach, obecnie są produkowane głównie z tworzyw sztucznych.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="pt">A vuvuzela (conhecida no Brasil como corneta ou cornetão e em partes de Moçambique como xipalapala) é um aerofone cilíndrico de cerca de um metro de comprimento, usada por torcedores em jogos de futebol. As vuvuzelas ganharam forte exposição na mídia devido à Copa do Mundo 2010 realizada na África do Sul e a função sonora que exercem para comemorar gols ou durante a partida.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">Die Vuvuzela [vuvuˈzɛla] (Zulu) (auf Setswana manchmal auch Lepatata genannt) ist ein Blasinstrument und gilt als ein Symbol des südafrikanischen Fußballs.Aufgrund ihrer Tonerzeugung gehört die Vuvuzela zu den Blechblasinstrumenten. Das ursprünglich aus Blech, inzwischen allerdings meist aus Kunststoff gefertigte Instrument besteht aus einer konischen, bis zu einem Meter langen Röhre, die an ihrem engen Ende mit einem integrierten Trichtermundstück versehen ist. Die Mensur der Röhre, die einem Exponentialtrichter angenähert ist, und die Mensur des Mundstücks sind darauf ausgelegt, den Grundton der Naturtonreihe mit sehr hoher Lautstärke spielen zu können.Mit Vuvuzelas können in einem Abstand von einem Meter Schalldruckpegel von 120 dB(A) und direkt am Schalltrichter sogar bis zu 131 dB(A) erreicht werden.Einige auf dem europäischen Markt vertriebenen dreiteiligen Vuvuzelas sind mit einem Schalldämpfer versehen, der den Schalldruckpegel um ca. 13 dB(A) reduziert. Messungen des TÜV Nord auf einer Stadiontribüne ergaben einen maximalen Wert von 103,8 dB(A). Realisiert wird die Schallreduktion durch eine mehrere Zentimeter lange Querschnittsreduktion direkt hinter dem Mundstück. Allerdings können diese Schalldämpfer ausgebaut werden.Das Überblasen auf höhere Naturtöne ist grundsätzlich möglich, wird jedoch durch die Mensur von Röhre und Mundstück erschwert. Daher lassen sich in der Regel nur wenige Töne auf dem Instrument spielen, die zudem nicht immer gleich bleibend intonieren. Wird auf der Vuvuzela der Grundton gespielt, ähnelt deren Klang dem Trompetenlaut eines Elefanten. Vielfach in Stadien eingesetzt, klingen sie dagegen wie ein „Hornissen-Schwarm“.Die Herkunft des Namens ist umstritten. Er könnte aus der Bantusprache isiZulu stammen und „Krach machen“ bedeuten oder von dem Klang vuvu, der erzeugt wird, oder aus einem Slang der Townships, wo er vom Wort für „Dusche“ – hier im Sinne von „jemanden in Musik duschen“ beziehungsweise wegen der Duschkopf-Form der Instrumente – abgeleitet wäre.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="fr">La vuvuzela, appelée lepatata en setswana, parfois francisée en vouvouzela, est une corne d'environ 70 centimètres de long, popularisée dans les années 1990 par les supporters des deux clubs de Soweto en Afrique du Sud : les Kaizer Chiefs (équipés du modèle jaune) et les Orlando Pirates (équipés du modèle noir et blanc). Elle a acquis une renommée internationale lors de la Coupe des confédérations 2009 et est omniprésente lors de la Coupe du monde de football de 2010, devenant un symbole de cette dernière, en même temps qu'un sujet de controverses à cause du bourdonnement incessant qu'elle génère pendant les matchs et leur retransmission.L'étymologie du nom est imprécise, soit du mot zoulou pour « faire du bruit », soit d'une onomatopée (« vou-vou ») imitant le son produit.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="ar">فوفوزيلا (Vuvuzela كما تلفظ حسب لغة زولو) عبارة عن آلة نفخ تستخدم عادة في ملاعب كرة القدم في جنوب أفريقيا. تسمى أيضاً ليباتاتا Lepatata حسب لغة سيتسوانا.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">The vuvuzela /vuːvuːˈzɛlə/, also known as lepatata Mambu (its Tswana name), is a plastic horn, about 65 centimetres (2 ft) long, which produces a loud monotone note, typically around B♭ 3 (the B♭ below middle C). Some models are made in two parts to facilitate storage, and this design also allows pitch variation. Many types of vuvuzela, made by several manufacturers, may produce various intensity and frequency outputs. The intensity of these outputs depends on the blowing technique and pressure exerted.Traditionally made and inspired from a kudu horn, the vuvuzela was used to summon distant villagers to attend community gatherings. The vuvuzela is most used at football matches in South Africa, and it has become a symbol of South African football as the stadiums are filled with its sound. The intensity of the sound caught the attention of the global football community during the 2009 FIFA Confederations Cup in anticipation of South Africa hosting the 2010 FIFA World Cup.The vuvuzela has been the subject of controversy when used by spectators at football matches. Its high sound pressure levels at close range can lead to permanent hearing loss for unprotected ears after exposure, with a sound level of 120 dB(A) (the threshold of pain) at 1 metre (3.3 ft) from the device opening.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="es">Una vuvuzela (en zulú, también conocida como lepatata en setsuana) es una especie de trompeta larga o corneta hecha de material plástico, utilizada por los aficionados para animar a sus equipos o clubes deportivos. Ha sido usada desde los años 60 en diferentes estadios del mundo sin ningún nombre específico, pero debe su nombre africano a que fue popularizada en tiempos de la Copa Mundial de Fútbol de 2010 en Sudáfrica. Algunos timbres que produce son similares al barritar de un elefante o al zumbido de una abeja.Normalmente suena en nota Si Bemol. En español, ha de escribirse "vuvucela", según las reglas ortográficas españolas</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string">ブブゼラ (Vuvuzela) は、南アフリカの楽器。ツワナ語ではレパタタ (lepatata) とも呼ばれる。“ブブセラ”と表記するのは間違い。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="zh">呜呜祖拉（Vuvuzela，在茨瓦纳语中又被称为“lepatata”），又称呜呜泽拉、巫巫宰拉、巫巫塞拉、呜呜赛拉、巫巫兹拉、嗚嗚聲喇、呼呼塞拉、瓦瓦祖拉、嗚嗚些拿、嗚嗚茲拉、烏烏茲拉、非洲笛，長喇叭或嗚嗚號，是一种长约一米的号角。南非的球迷常在足球比赛上吹奏，吹响呜呜祖拉需要一定的唇部技巧和肺活量；吹奏呜呜祖拉时，會發出單調聲音(B♭)，类似于雾笛或大象的声音。呜呜祖拉的使用已引起爭議。它發出的聲音可能會對聽力構成永久損害，同時也會引起一些安全問題，例如會令在球場的觀眾無法聽見緊急疏散的宣佈，以及比咳嗽和吶喊較易導致感冒及流感病毒的大規模傳播。2010年世界盃足球賽部份的實況播音員把呜呜祖拉的聲音稱為「令人烦躁的」、「一群嘈吵的大象的狂奔」、「一群極喧鬧的蝗蟲」、「將被宰殺的山羊叫聲」和「一個充滿憤怒的蜜蜂的巨大蜂箱」。這種樂器響度可以達到127分貝 對未作保護的人耳有極大傷害。2010年6月14日一種新型的呜呜祖拉問世，聲稱通過調整唇片使其音量下降了20分貝。</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/abstract</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="nl">Een vuvuzela is een blaasinstrument dat vooral in Zuid-Afrika populair is onder voetbalfans en dat in 2010, naar aanleiding van het wereldkampioenschap voetbal 2010, ook in veel andere landen bekend is geworden.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageID</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">6019166</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageRevisionID</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">595415476</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/classification</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Brass
* Wind
* Brass
* Aerophone</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/range</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Varies by instrument, typically around B♭</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/related</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bugle</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/related</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kudu</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/title</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Noisy Vuvuzelas cause concern</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/title</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Vuvuzela note</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/description</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">A standard short  vuvuzela plays a single B note.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/description</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Voice of America report on the impact of vuvuzelas at the 2010 FIFA World Cup.</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/filename</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">2010-06-14+02:00</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/filename</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Vuvuzela single note.ogg</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/hornbostelSachs</sem:predicate><sem:object datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#decimal">423.1209999999999809</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/hornbostelSachsDesc</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">Tubular end-blown trumpet with mouthpiece</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/property/imageCapt</sem:predicate><sem:object xml:lang="en">A modern plastic Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageExternalLink</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7X3fkvhd-5g</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageExternalLink</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://www.thedailypage.com/isthmus/article.php?article=33472</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageExternalLink</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://www.thefirstpost.co.uk/64381,in-pictures,news-in-pictures,vuvuzela-day-in-pictures-bafana-world-cup-football-south-africa</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageExternalLink</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/world/africa/10312794.stm</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://dbpedia.org/ontology/wikiPageExternalLink</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/0,1518,820452,00.html</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://af.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ar.dbpedia.org/resource/فوفوزيلا</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://arz.dbpedia.org/resource/فوفوزيلا</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://az.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://bg.dbpedia.org/resource/Вувузела</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://bn.dbpedia.org/resource/ভুভুজেলা</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ca.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://co.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://cy.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://da.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://eo.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzelo</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://et.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://fa.dbpedia.org/resource/ووووزلا</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://fi.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://gl.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://he.dbpedia.org/resource/וובוזלה</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://hr.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://hu.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://is.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://jv.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://lb.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://lmo.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://lt.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://lv.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://mk.dbpedia.org/resource/Вувузела</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ml.dbpedia.org/resource/വുവുസേല</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ms.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://nds.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ne.dbpedia.org/resource/भुभुजेला</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://nn.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://no.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://oc.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ro.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Вувузела</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://simple.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sk.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sl.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sq.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sr.dbpedia.org/resource/Вувузела</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple><sem:triple><sem:subject>http://sv.dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:subject><sem:predicate>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#sameAs</sem:predicate><sem:object>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vuvuzela</sem:object></sem:triple></sem:triples>